(
"ai_sub_version": "2.8.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"ollama_search": (
"key": "**********"
),
"web_search_tool": "ollama",
"validation_buffer_ms": 1000
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
HAPPY MUSIC
作詞：ふじのマナミ 作曲・編曲：片岡嗣実
[Song: HAPPY MUSIC / Lyrics: Manami Fujino
Music & Arrangement: Tsugumi Kataoka]
どうかししてる
Something's wrong with me...
また同じシャツを
Looking for that same shirt again
いないはずの
In a place you shouldn't be,
人込みに捜してた
I was searching for you in the crowd
だれといても
No matter who I'm with,
何を話しても
no matter what we're talking about
映るすべて
Everything I see,
やだ またかさねている
oh no, I'm projecting you onto it again
名前しか知らない
I only know your name,
なのにね こんなに
and yet, why am I so...
気になるの……これって もしかして
Curious about you... could this be...?
ほら たった今 あたしのなかで
Look, just now, inside of me,
響くよ ハッピーミュージック
it's ringing out, Happy Music
運命の針を 胸に落として 奏でる
Dropping the needle of fate onto my heart, playing it
大事な日も まじめな時も
On important days, even when I'm serious,
手加減なしの パワープレイ
a no-holds-barred power play
誰よりも先 あなたを見つけたくて
I want to find you before anyone else
ダーリン 今度も あのシャツきてきて
Darling, wear that shirt next time too
こんぬいー！
Kon-nui!
ホロライブ3期生の 不知火フレアでーす！
I'm Shiranui Flare from Hololive 3rd Gen!
【 #不知火フレア生誕祭2026 】
BEMANI楽曲３D LIVE！
[#ShiranuiFlareBirthday2026]
BEMANI Song 3D LIVE!
不知火フレア生誕祭2026
BEMANI楽曲3Dライブ、始まりましたー！
Shiranui Flare Birthday 2026
BEMANI Song 3D Live has begun!
1曲目、Happy Musicをゲーム尺でお届けしましたが、
どうでしたか？
The first song was 'Happy Music', the game version.
How did you like it?
今回はこの衣装をポエットちゃんに寄せて、
ちょっと天使っぽい感じにしてみました。
I matched my outfit to Poet-chan this time,
to give it a bit of an angelic feel.
Happy Musicは大好きな楽曲なので、
今回歌わせていただきました！
I love 'Happy Music' so much,
so I'm glad I got to sing it!
タイトルにもあるように、今回は全て
BEMANI楽曲で構成されたライブとなっています。
As the title suggests, this entire live
is made up of BEMANI songs.
コナミさんに熱意をお伝えしたところ、
全面的にご協力いただけることになりました！
After sharing my passion with Konami,
they agreed to cooperate with us fully!
なんと、見てください！デデーン！
今回のステージ、すごいんですよ！
Look! Ta-da!
This stage is absolutely amazing!
コナミさんから素材をお借りして、
全て用意していただいたりしまして...
We borrowed assets from Konami,
and they prepared everything for us...
めちゃめちゃ可愛い！フレアは「ポッパー」なので、
全体的にPop'n Music風なんですけど、
It's so cute! Since I'm a 'Popper',
it has a very Pop'n Music style,
DDRや下のキーボードはノスタルジアか、
キーボードマニアか...どっちなんだい！って感じで、
but there's also DDR and a keyboard... is it
Nostalgia or Keyboardmania? Which one could it be?!
ここもサウンドボルテックスみたいに、
BEMANI要素を詰め詰めにしたステージになりました！
Even this part is like Sound Voltex.
We've packed the stage with BEMANI elements!
本当にありがとうございます！
完全にフレアのやりたい放題なライブになってます。
Thank you so much!
This live is basically me doing whatever I want.
これが結果的に嬉しいお知らせに繋がるかも...
繋がらないかも。それは後ほどのお楽しみに！
This might lead to some happy news...
or it might not. Look forward to finding out later!
ハッシュタグは
#不知火フレア生誕祭2026 でございます。
The hashtag is
#ShiranuiFlareBirthday2026.
こちらでスクショやポストなど、
いろいろ反応してもらえると嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you could share screenshots
and posts using that hashtag!
この後のセットリストは、完全に私の好みと
独断と偏見で選んでいるので、お楽しみに！
I chose the rest of the setlist based on my own
preferences and bias, so please look forward to it!
知らない方も「こんな曲があるんだ」と
知ってもらえたら嬉しいなと思います。
I'd be glad if people who don't know the songs
could discover them here.
明日にはポップンやボルテをしに行こう！
という気持ちになってくれたら最高です！
I'd love it if this made you want to go
play Pop'n or Sound Voltex tomorrow!
最後まで見てくれないと泣いちゃうかも...
シクシク... エンエン... 泣いちゃうかもー！
Please watch until the end, or I might cry!
*sob sob*... I might just cry!
ナ・カ・ナ・イ・デ
本当の孤独も知らない
P-l-e-a-s-e d-o n-o-t c-r-y
You don't know what it really means to be alone
まだ淡い花びらに
涙の粒　抱えたまま…
Like dew on pale flower petals
My tears still cling on...
Pink Rose
[Song: Pink Rose]
ah　さわらないで
暖かなその手は
Ah, don't you touch me
Those hands of yours are so warm
わたしのすべて狂わす
They make me all mixed-up inside
ne　許さないで
傷口押さえて
Hey, I won't forgive you
For trying to patch up the wound you left
微笑んでる　あなたがいる
もう　帰れないね
That smile on your face that you're giving to me
Well, I can't go back from it now
堕ちてく時の　甘い香り
All the times that I fell for that sweet fragrance
繰り返すたびにひどくなる
It grows worse each moment and it's happening again
ダ・キ・シ・メ・テ
いまだけ　好きだってフリして
H-o-l-d m-e i-n y-o-u-r a-r-m-s
And just this once, pretend you have love in your heart
たった　ひとつだけなら
ぜんぶ　ぜんぶ　いらない
That's the #1 thing that I wish
I don't, I don't want anything else
Bloomin'like a Rose
本当の孤独も知らない
Bloomin' like a rose
You don't know what it really means to be alone
まだ淡い花びらに
涙の粒　抱えたまま
Like dew on pale flower petals
My tears still cling on
キスするときのわたしの顔
My face when we kiss
もっときれいに見せたいだけ
I just want to show you a more beautiful me
抱きしめて いつでもかわいいフリして
Hold me tight, always pretending to be cute
真っ赤に色づく日を ずっとずっと待ってる
I've been waiting forever for the day I turn bright red
泣かないで 本当の自分を知らずに
Don't cry without even knowing your true self
まだ淡い花びらに 夢の重さ抱えたまま
Still holding the weight of dreams on these pale petals
落ちていく時の甘い香り
The sweet scent as time falls away
繰り返すたびにひどくなる
It gets worse every time it repeats
抱きしめて 今だけ好きだってフリして
Hold me tight, pretend you love me just for now
ただひとつだけなら 全部全部いらない
If I can't have that one thing, I don't need anything at all
Bloomin' like a Rose 本当の孤独を知らない
Bloomin' like a Rose, you don't know true loneliness
まだ淡い花びらに 涙の粒抱えたまま
Still holding droplets of tears on these pale petals
チェイス！チェイス！チェイス！
[Title: Chase! Chase! Chase!]
あとそう3センチ
Just 3 more centimeters
キミのくちびるまで
Until I reach your lips
妄想渦巻く イカした夢はなぜか
For some reason, this cool dream filled with delusions...
これからってトコで いつも覚める
...always ends just when it's getting good
わずかに10センチ
Merely 10 centimeters
伸ばす腕ムナしく
My reaching arm is in vain
閉まる扉 ホームに独りきり
The doors close, leaving me alone on the platform
キミとガラス越しに 目と目が合う
Our eyes meet with you through the glass
ああ ここはひとつ笑うしかない
Ah, all I can do here is laugh
白線のうしろ 立ち上がった
Behind the white line, I stood up
不覚にも涙がこぼれても
Even if tears should accidentally fall
ここはひとつ笑うしかない
All I can do here is laugh
いつかキミまで 追いつくかな
I wonder if I'll eventually catch up to you
脱いで捨てちゃうほど
To the point where I'd just throw it away
かわりはいるよなんて
Saying there's always a replacement...
どうなの？おじいちゃんおばあちゃん
How about it? Grandpa, Grandma
すぐに投げちゃ いけないんだよね
You shouldn't just give up right away, right?
今も昔も これからずっと
Now, in the past, and from now on forever
かわりのボクは どこにもいない
There's no replacement for me anywhere
もう ここはひとつ笑うしかない
Now, all I can do here is laugh
わかりあえる その日が来るまで
Until the day we can understand each other
いつか君まで 追い越すから
I'll eventually overtake even you
いつでも どこでも 狙い撃ち
Anytime, anywhere, I'll take my shot
ふたりの距離は 縮まるかな
I wonder if the distance between us will shrink
ノドの乾きも 忘れたまま
While still forgetting the thirst in my throat
笑わないよ Chase!
I won't smile, Chase!
君の代わりは ひとりもいない
There's not a single person who can replace you
君の代わりじゃ ボクはいらない
If it's a replacement for you, I don't want it
不覚にも 涙がこぼれても
Even if tears should accidentally fall
もうここは ひとつ 笑うしかない
There's nothing left to do but laugh now
今も 昔も これからずっと
Now, in the past, and forever from now on
代わりのボクは どこにもいない
There's no replacement for me anywhere
あぁ そうだったのかって
Ah, I see it was like that
きっと きっと
Surely, surely
分かり合える その日が来るから
Because the day we understand each other will come
Chase! 今日もひとつ 笑うしかない
Chase! Today, there's nothing left but to laugh
闇に放り込んだ
Thrust into the darkness
想い 届いていますか？
Are my feelings reaching you?
吟人恋歌
[Title: Ginjin Renka - Singer's Love Song]
浅い夢の醒め際に 毎日
Every day, as I wake from shallow dreams
伝う 涙の理由は どこから
Where does the reason for these streaming tears come from?
きっと戻ってくるよと 頬を撫でる手は 冷たくて
The hand stroking my cheek, saying you'll surely return, was so cold
ぎゅっと広い背中を 抱きしめた
I tightly hugged your broad back
謡え 謡え 通い路恋歌 たとえ声は しなくとも
Sing, sing, the Path Love Song, even if no voice is heard
届け 届け 通い路恋歌
Reach, reach, the Path Love Song
愛する人の為 ずっと笑顔で居るから
For the one I love, I'll always be smiling
淡い日々の思い出に 毎日
Every day, in the memories of faint days
すがるふたりの姿は 儚げ
The figures of the two of us clinging on seem so fleeting
ぐっと抑え続けた 瞳の奥のやさしさが
The kindness deep in my eyes that I kept holding back
ふと通り咲く 刹那に溢れる
Suddenly blooms as it passes, overflowing in an instant
止まれ 止まれ 防人恋歌 たとえ声は しなくとも
Stop, stop, the Guardian's Love Song, even if no voice is heard
届け 届け 通い路恋歌
Reach, reach, the Path Love Song
愛する人の為 ずっと笑顔で居るから
For the one I love, I'll always be smiling
貴方の為 君の為 また出会う日までの約束
For you, for my dear, a promise until the day we meet again
どんな思いが 馳せようと 笑顔で居よう
No matter what thoughts race through, let's stay smiling
遠く 遠く 分かれても
Even if we're separated far, far away
辛い時は 歌に乗せて
When it's hard, put it into a song
ずっと待っているよと しがみつく手は 震えてて
Saying I'll always wait for you, my clinging hands were trembling
もっと強く深く深く 抱きしめた
I hugged you even tighter and deeper
謡え 謡え 通い路恋歌 たとえ声が 枯れても
Sing, sing, the Path Love Song, even if my voice withers
笑え 笑え 通い路恋歌 暖かい陽は まだ遠く
Laugh, laugh, the Path Love Song, the warm sun is still far away
ずっと ずっと 謡えるのは 君の声が するから
The reason I can sing forever and ever is because I hear your voice
届け 届け 防人恋歌
Reach, reach, the Guardian's Love Song
愛する人の為 ずっと笑顔で居るから
For the one I love, I'll always be smiling
はい、みなさん見てますか？
Yes, everyone, are you watching?
はい、ということでですね、
Yes, so regarding that,
あきちゃんとはピンクローズを、
with Aki-chan we did Pink Rose,
リリィカとはチェイスチェイスチェイスを...
and with Lilyka we did Chase! Chase! Chase!...
はい はい はい はい！
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
防人恋歌をソロで歌わせていただきました！
I sang "Sakimori Renka" as a solo!
はい。ちょっとね、どうしてこの曲を選んだかみたいなのは…
Yes. Well, as for why I chose this song...
その、世代じゃないんですけど、この好きな曲とか…
I'm not from that generation, but it's a song I like...
好きな曲とか、合いそうな曲、あとはみんなが…
...songs I like, songs that suit me, and also what everyone...
慣れ親しんだポップンといえば、みたいな曲だったり…
...is familiar with, like a classic "Pop'n" song...
ま、Pink Roseはキーボードマニアの曲なんですけど。
Well, "Pink Rose" is actually a Keyboardmania song.
でもみんな好きな曲をちょっと選曲したり…
But I selected songs that everyone likes...
アクチャはバラードなのでね、とか…
Since "Akucha" is a ballad, and...
防人恋歌は、思い出があったらヤバいけど…
"Sakimori Renka"... it would be crazy if there were memories, but...
好きな曲だったので、ちょっとチョイスさせていただきました。
...it was a song I liked, so I chose it.
いや本当に、でも難しかったです。
Man, it was really difficult though.
でもですね、今日はですね、衣装変わりましたけれども…
But anyway, today, my outfit has changed, but...
今日はなんとですね、私の希望で…
Today, at my request...
今回ポップンミュージック ハイ・チェアーズを遊べると聞いたんですけど！
I heard I can play Pop'n Music High-Cheers this time!
え？どこで？どこにあるんでしょう？ちょっと探してみましょうか。
Huh? Where? Where is it? Let's go look for it.
どこどこどこどこどこどこどこどこ…
Where, where, where, where, where...
あ！これは！うわ！
Oh! This is it! Wow!
会いたかった！大好き！
I've wanted to see this! I love it!
え、すごいよ、この技術はすごい技術ですよ。
This technology is amazing, really amazing.
皆さん、なかなかVTuber実機で遊んでいるところを見る機会がないと思うんですけど。
I don't think you often get to see a VTuber playing on an actual machine.
いや、本当にコナミさんと運営さん、本当にありがとうございます。
Really, Konami and the management, thank you so much.
今回はね、こちらの可愛い筐体で遊ばせていただくんですけど…
This time, I'll be playing on this cute cabinet...
皆さんこのステージ気づきましたか？こちらはですね…
Did everyone notice this stage? This is...
なんとスピーカー、このスピーカーとかですね、ステージ側にもあるんですけど。
...actually speakers, these speakers are also on the stage side.
こちら合わせていただいたりして、コナミさんがステージ素材をご用意してくださったんですよ！
They matched them up, and Konami even provided the stage assets!
いや本当に本当にありがとうございます。
I'm truly, truly grateful.
なんかコナミさんにおんぶにだっこで、本当にすみません。
I feel like I'm leaning so much on Konami, I'm sorry.
私の今日やりたいことをたくさんお願いして、ダメ元でお願いしたらね…
I made many requests for things I wanted to do today, and...
たくさん応えてくださって、本当にありがとうございます。
...they said yes to so many, thank you so much.
頭が上がりませんが、せっかくなんでね…
I can't thank you enough, but since I'm here...
早速ちょっと遊ばせていただこうかなと思います。
...I'd like to jump right in and play.
じゃ、ちょっといいですか？とりあえずハッピーバースデーとか叩かせていただいて。
Well, shall we? I'll start by tapping along to "Happy Birthday."
ポンポンポンポン…この画面にクラッカーが映ったりするんですけど。
*Tapping*... Look, crackers are appearing on the screen.
今回は、自分のマイカードで遊ばせていただけるということで。
This time, I'm able to play using my own "My Card."
あ、ちょっと暗証番号は見せられないんで、ちょっと待ってくださいね。
Oh, I can't show my PIN, so please wait a moment.
はい、こうしてちょちょいのちょいと、入れさせていただきますよ。
There, I'll just put it in real quick.
遊ぶモードを選ぶ…ノーマルモード！
Choosing the mode... Normal Mode!
わ！ポップンミュージックだ！いつも遊ばせていただいております。
Wow! It's Pop'n Music! I play this all the time.
お世話になっております、ありがとうございます。
Thanks for all the great times, and thank you!
ということでですね、今日は推しを使わせていただきます。
So, I'll be using my favorite character today.
ちょっと今回はボーカルライブということで、ボーカル縛りで…
Since this is a "Vocal Live," I thought I'd pick vocal-focused...
ちょっと３曲を選ばせていただこうと思ったんですけど。
...three songs for today.
今日のラインナップ、３曲は…
Today's three-song lineup is...
ポップンミュージックで一番好きな曲、「音」でまず遊ばせていただこうかと思います。
I'll start with my favorite Pop'n Music song, "Oto."
もう大好きなんですよね。でもちょっとハイパーで許していただきたいと思います。
I just love it so much. Please let me play on "Hyper" difficulty though.
今日選ぶ３曲の中で、個人的には一番難しい、難しいです。
Of the three songs I picked today, this is personally the hardest.
難しかったんですけど、もう一番大好きな曲なので、ちょっと選ばせていただきました。
It's difficult, but I picked it because it's my absolute favorite.
ボーカルでこの曲選んでいいのかって話なんですけど。
I wonder if it's okay to pick this for a vocal segment though.
いや、この静かに始まる感じとね…
Man, this quiet opening...
あの最後に来る縦連とかが、難しいんですよね。
Those vertical rolls at the end are so tough.
Are you ready?
これ配信バフでフルコンとかできないかな？無理か。
I wonder if I can get a full combo with the "streamer's luck"? Probably not.
ちょ、ちょ、音ゲーマー…
Wait, as a rhythm gamer...
あ、コンボ繋がっている時だけは喋れないと思ったんですけど、切れちゃいましたね。
Ah, I thought I couldn't talk while keeping a combo, but it broke.
あ、右手に推し、左手に推し、幸せですね。
Ah, my favorite character on the right and left, I'm so happy.
あ！縦連が苦手なんです！許してください！
Ah! I'm bad at vertical rolls! Forgive me!
Right now, what's your way!
この曲も
This song too...
歌いたかったですね
...is one I wanted to sing.
もしまた何か機会があったら
If there is another chance,
歌わせてください
please let me sing it.
どうしてもちょっと後半がグズグズになってしまう
The second half always ends up becoming a mess.
あー神曲！
Ah, a god-tier song!
ここがきつい！
This part is tough!
あー、なんか取れたかな？大丈夫かな？
Ah, did I get something? Is it okay?
あー、一番、フレアが一番好きな曲です
Ah, this is Flare's number one favorite song.
これで「音」と読みます
This character is read as 'Oto' (Sound).
あー大好き
Ah, I love it.
あの、推しです
He's my favorite.
推しのMZDさんです、これどちらも
It's my favorite, MZD, in both of these.
今日はですね、あの、選ぶ3曲のうちの2曲が
So today, two out of the three songs I chose...
ちょっとMZDの曲なんですけど
...are actually MZD songs.
どうしてもみんなとやりたかったやつもあって
But there was one I really wanted to do with everyone,
ちょっとそれ最後にしたいなと思ったんで、ちょっとMZDで挟んじゃうんですけど
so I'll do that last, and sandwich it between MZD songs.
今回ちょっとライブでは歌わないのですが
I won't be singing this one at the live show today, but...
やはりね、あの、ポップンといえばの中で、結構ナデシコロックじゃないかっていう方も
...when you think of Pop'n, many of you would say Nadeshiko Rock is the one,
たくさんいらっしゃったので
and since there were so many requests,
ちょっとナデシコロックを叩かせていただこうかと思います
I thought I'd play Nadeshiko Rock.
よろしくお願いします
Please enjoy.
オッケー！
Okay!
凛として咲く花の如く
Rin toshite Saku Hana no Gotoku
Are you ready?
譜面もいいですからね
The chart is great too.
みんなの一番いい曲のひとつですね
It's one of everyone's favorite songs.
一番いい曲なんてなんぼあったっていいですからね
You can never have too many 'best' songs.
フレア今日何回一番いい曲のひとつって言ってるでしょう
I wonder how many times I've said 'one of the best' today.
口癖みたいに言ってると思います
I think it's becoming a habit.
フレア、エルフレにもたくさん知ってもらいたいんですよね
Flare wants the Elfriends to know about them too.
コナミさんの神曲にはたくさんいい曲があるということを
That there are so many god-tier songs from Konami.
ジャンジャン、ジャンジャンジャン
Janjan, janjanjan.
SE歌いがち
I tend to sing the sound effects.
ここがね、この後！
This part, right after this!
こういうところ好きですよね
I love parts like this.
いい曲であり譜面もいい
It's a great song and a great chart.
ちょっとなんかお馬さんパカパカみたいな感じで
It's like a horse going clip-clop.
ここ楽しいですよね
This part is fun.
ということで、ギリギリ、スコアが9万点いかないみたいな
So, just barely, the score didn't reach 90,000.
これちょっと悔しいですね
That's a bit frustrating.
はい、凛として咲く花の如く、アニューレコードだそうで
Yes, 'Rin toshite Saku Hana no Gotoku', apparently a new record.
これ自分のカード、マイカードなので
This is my card, my own card.
はい、ニューレコードだそうです。配信バフなんでしょうか。ありがとうございました
Yes, a new record. Must be the stream buff. Thank you!
最後はですね、みんなでどうしても叫びたかったあの曲といったら二択だと思うんですけど
Finally, when it comes to that song we all really want to shout along to...
ちょっとどうしてもみんなと叫びたい
...I really want to shout with everyone.
ハンズアップに決まってるじゃないですか！
It's gotta be Hands Up, obviously!
これ知らない方はね、カウントの後、カウントあります。4, 3, 2, 1で
For those who don't know, there's a count. At 4, 3, 2, 1...
サンバイスクリームなので
...it's 'Sun-by-ice-cream!'
皆さんで叫びましょう
Let's all shout together.
叫べるかな？ちょっと45だけどこれ45じゃないんじゃないかっていうか最後がすごく難しいですよね
I wonder if we can do it? It's level 45, but feels higher. The ending is so hard.
最後落としたらごめんなさい
Sorry if I fail at the end.
これをみんなで叫ぶのが夢だったんですよね
It was my dream to shout this with everyone.
ゴールドラッシュとね、どっちやろうかなって迷いましたらば、ちょっとセカンドヘブンにしました
I was torn between this and Gold Rush, but I decided to go with Second Heaven.
なんかボーカル縛りと言いながら、2曲英語っていう...
Even though I said I'd stick to vocals, two of the songs are in English...
Countdown.. eight.. seven.. six.. five.. four.. three.. two.. one
サンバイアイスクリーム！
Three times ice cream!
みんなちゃんと見ました？
Did everyone see that properly?
もう1回やりますからね
I'm going to do it again, okay?
正しい歌詞はぜひ調べてください
Please look up the correct lyrics.
生きがいなんだ。サンバイアイスクリームって言うことが生きがいなんだ。
It's what I live for. Saying "Three times ice cream!" is my reason for being.
みんなはこの配信を見た後明日はポップンやりに行きましょうね
Everyone, after watching this stream, let's go play Pop'n tomorrow.
人の配信見てるとやりたくなりますからね
Watching someone else's stream makes you want to play it yourself.
ちょっと恥ずかしいんですけど手元見られてんの
It's a bit embarrassing having you watch my hands.
サンバイアイスクリーム！
Three times ice cream!
急に叫ぶよ
I'll shout it out of nowhere.
ちょっとここむずい
This part is a bit hard.
ありがとうございました
Thank you very much.
みんなでサンバイアイスクリームが言えて幸せだ
I'm so happy we could all say "Three times ice cream!" together.
いや本当にありがとうございました
No, really, thank you so much.
あ、待ってでも3曲終わっちゃった
Ah, wait, the three songs are already over.
終わっちゃってよー
They're already finished!
楽しかったー
That was so much fun!
今日はね、あの3曲しか遊べないので、ここで終わってしまうんですけど...
Today, since I can only play three songs, it's going to end here...
実況プレイはここで終わっちゃうんですけど
The gameplay part ends here, but...
やだやだ！ポップンと離れたくないよー！
No, no! I don't want to leave Pop'n!
フレア今日はもうポップンする！
Flare is going to keep playing Pop'n today!
ポップンと離れたくないよー！
I don't want to leave Pop'n behind!
ポップンしたいよー！
I want to play Pop'n!
まあないものしょうがないか
Well, it can't be helped if it's over.
ちょっと切り替えていきますか
Let's shift gears a bit.
この後もみんなの好きな一番いい曲たくさん歌いますので
After this, I'll be singing many of everyone's favorite best songs.
ちょっと楽しみにこの後も見ていただけたら嬉しいなって思います
So I hope you'll look forward to watching what's coming next.
じゃあみんな次に行くぞ
Alright everyone, let's move on to the next one!
次の曲は...
The next song is...
大見解
Daikenkai [Large Interpretations]
回転頭からない言語 ハイテンションと固いテンポ
Language not known from the rotating head, high tension and stiff tempo
I 先導するジャイケン5から大見解戦法
I lead from Jaiken 5, Daikenkai battle method
回転頭からない言語 ハイテンションと固いテンポ
Language not known from the rotating head, high tension and stiff tempo
I 先導するジャイケン5から大見解戦法
I lead from Jaiken 5, Daikenkai battle method
35+4÷2すらはじけぬコンパ好き達に
35 + 4 / 2 is not even split among party-lovers
あっさり鈍角にねじ込むさばけた音楽鬼は
Easily screwing into obtuse angles, the savvy music demon
どっからどこまでかわわからん？が音わけた理由(わけ)だ
I don't know from where to where? But it's the reason sound divided
どいつとこいつのしゃべくりが、垂らした汗ふきな
Which one and this one's chatter, wipe away the sweat that dripped
デンダン変化付けた×電波に乗る大変馬鹿げた発言にや
Dendan added changes, x, riding the radio waves at such a ridiculously foolish remark
グーを作りゃ人格すら変わる程にあがる心拍数は
If I make a rock, my personality even changes, the rising heart rate is
たっぷりあこぎだが、にょい棒を握る田と力として
Plenty greedy, but as the field and power to hold the Nyoibo staff
生まれたときから続けてきたこの遊び方
This way of playing I've continued since I was born
回転頭からない言語 ハイテンションと固いテンポ
Language not known from the rotating head, high tension and stiff tempo
I 先導するジャイケン5から大見解戦法
I lead from Jaiken 5, Daikenkai battle method
回転頭からない言語 ハイテンションと固いテンポ
Language not known from the rotating head, high tension and stiff tempo
I 先導するジャイケン5から大見解戦法
I lead from Jaiken 5, Daikenkai battle method
3通りから4通り 本道理より煩脳に
From 3 types to 4 types, more worldly desires than true reason
まかせたぎりを梱包し がっつり温厚に
Packed with the duty I left to it, firmly and calmly
本当にこの鈍行に またがっていれば don't worry
Really, if I'm straddling this slow train, don't worry
Don Pach Don Pach Don 今日で とことん交尾する日本島に
Don Pach Don Pach Don, today, on the Japanese island where we thoroughly mate
3通りから4通り 本道理より煩脳に
From 3 types to 4 types, more worldly desires than true reason
まかせたぎりを梱包し がっつり温厚に
Packed with the duty I left to it, firmly and calmly
本当にこの鈍行に またがっていれば don't worry
Really, if I'm straddling this slow train, don't worry
Don Pach Don Pach Don 今日で とことん交尾する日本島に
Don Pach Don Pach Don, today, on the Japanese island where we thoroughly mate
Don Pach Don Pach Don 今日で
Don Pach Don Pach Don, today...
とことん交尾する日本列島に
To the Japanese archipelago that copulates thoroughly,
そんなそんなそんな調子
Like that, like that, like that pace,
ぶち壊していくぜ 見本通りだば
I'll smash it up, just like the model!
O! K! M! E!
O! K! O!
M! E!
RICE! おこめこめ RICE!
RICE! Rice, rice, RICE!
O! K! O!
K! O!
M! E!
OKOME! おこめこめ RICE!
OKOME! Rice, rice, RICE!
SUPER POWER RELAXATION
1合150CC 正確無比に計ること
1 cup, 150cc—measure it with zero errors.
次に洗いだが直接米にお水をあてず二本指で
Next is washing; don't pour water directly, use two fingers.
お水を計りJOIN!するのだが その量米の1.2倍
Measure the water and JOIN! Set it to 1.2 times the rice.
その後は二時間ほどサディスティック(!)に お水に浸して
Then soak it for two hours... sadistically(!)
ジャーの電源ON！
Rice cooker power ON!
陽炎のようなスチーム
Steam rising like a heat haze.
底からかき混ぜて THE TIMING IS RIPE!
Stir from the bottom, THE TIMING IS RIPE!
おこめ おこめこめ ビタミン ミネラル 食物繊維
Rice, rice, rice, rice. Vitamins, minerals, dietary fiber.
おこめこめ おこめこめ
Rice, rice, rice, rice, rice, rice.
食べて どすこい＆どすこい おこめ おこめこめ
Eat and shout 'Dosukoi!' Rice, rice, rice, rice.
おすもうさんのPowerをGET おこめこめ おこめこめ
Get the power of a sumo wrestler! Rice, rice, rice, rice.
ああ 抱いて ロマンティックに NIGHT FLIGHT
Ah, hold me romantically on this NIGHT FLIGHT.
おこめ おこめこめ 米屋のあの子をたぶらかそう！
Rice, rice, rice, rice. Let's seduce that rice shop girl!
(GENIUS) 炊きほうだい
(GENIUS) Cook all you want.
(SEXY) 食べほうだい
(SEXY) Eat all you want.
(THRILLING) YEAH SO I LOVE YOU
おこめ おこめこめ SUPER ENERGY MIRACLE POWER
Rice, rice, rice, rice. SUPER ENERGY MIRACLE POWER!
おこめこめ おこめこめ ああん おこめ
Rice, rice, rice, rice. Aahn, rice...
おこめおいしい
Rice is delicious.
真昼と真夜中の間に立つ歌は
The song that stands between midday and midnight...
真っ白なゲームといって耳もとではしゃぐ
is a pure white game frolicking by your ear.
パーフェクト僕らは完璧...なんて軽い冗談だった
Perfect, we are perfect... what a simple joke that was.
いつも答えは127の項目
The answer is always among 127 items.
アスファルト蹴りあげたらトランプで決めて
After kicking up the asphalt, decide it with cards.
急ぎ足で駆け出すのさ 今すぐバスで
Run off with a brisk pace, take the bus right now.
そしてホームシック抱えながら人々は目指す
And while carrying homesickness, people aim ahead.
行き先はスマートに決めて 願いを叶えたいのなら
Choose your destination smartly, if you want your wish granted.
真夏と真冬の間に生まれた歌は
The song born between midsummer and midwinter...
まったりなカーブ描いてどこまでも進む
draws a relaxed curve and goes ahead anywhere.
パーフェクト全ては同じ...似たもの同士だった
Perfect, everything's the same... we were like-minded.
いつも答えは同じ音なんだ
The answer is always the same sound.
ソフトロックで暴れたら
If you go wild with soft rock,
トークバックで yeah!
then talk back, yeah!
差し出したルール 12月のスポーツ
The rules held out, December's sports.
バジルパスタの試食
Tasting basil pasta.
明日の噂話をトランクに詰めて
Packing tomorrow's gossip into the trunk.
逆回しでやり直すのさ 悪い性格
Starting over in reverse—it's a bad personality.
それでホームシック語りながら人々は祈る
Talking of being homesick, people offer their prayers.
行先は満ちあふれてる 誰かが待ちわびるから
Destinations are overflowing, for someone is waiting.
オレンジノイズ 浴びながら
Bathing in orange noise
ショートカットで
In short-cut
yeah!
新しいブーム
A new boom
聞き飽きたフレーズ
Phrases I'm tired of hearing
バブルアワーの法則
The law of Bubble Hour
さあ明日の噂話
Now, rumors of tomorrow
トラックに乗せて
Loading onto the truck
風に乗せてばらまくのさ
Riding the wind, scattering them
誰の計画？
Whose plan?
そしてホームシック
And then homesick
笑いながら
While laughing
人々は迷う
People are lost
行き先はそれぞれさ皆
Destinations are various for everyone
旅の途中なんだから
Because we're in the middle of a journey
風に乗って羽ばたくのは
Flapping wings in the wind
鳥の計画
The birds' plan
行き先はスピードを上げて
Speeding up toward the destination
この先もまだ続くなら
If it still continues ahead
続くなら...
If it continues...
はい、ということで、聴いていただきました曲は...
Yes, so, the songs you just heard...
ジャンル名で言ってもいいですか？ヒップロック、オコメタル、ソフトロックということで
May I say them by genre name? Hip Rock, Okometal, Soft Rock.
ポルカと1曲、バカタレサーカスで2曲ということで
One song with Polka, and two with Bakatare Circus.
なんか、オコメタルとかね、バカタレサーカスでどうしてもやりたかったんですよね
I really wanted to do Okometal with Bakatare Circus.
でも、やっぱり歌のうまいメンバーなんでね、皆さん集まってソフトロックとかで暴れ散らかしたりしたいなと思ったり
But they are such good singers, so I wanted everyone to gather and go wild with Soft Rock...
ポルカをね、やっぱりDes-ROW好きということで、Des-ROWさんの曲を一緒に歌いたいなと思いましたんで
As for Polka, she loves Des-ROW, so I wanted to sing a Des-ROW song together.
このメンバーで選曲させていただきましたー！
I chose the songs with these members!
ゲストはね、まだまだ、あの、まだまだって言ったらあれですね、まだいるので
Guests... there are still... well, it's strange to say "still", but there are more.
お楽しみに、ということなんですけど
So please look forward to it.
ま、ちょっと早いんですけど、先にですね、今回、ちょっとグッズの紹介をさせていただいてもよろしいでしょうか？
Well, it's a bit early, but first, may I introduce the merchandise this time?
また後でですね、あの、グッズの紹介もまた改めてさせていただきます
I'll introduce the goods again properly later.
えー、ではですね、いきます！
So, here we go!
不知火フレア 誕生日記念 2026
[Title: Shiranui Flare Birthday Celebration 2026]
まずは1つ目、マフラータオル！
First one, Muffler Towel!
イラストは、わっふる子さんに描いていただきました。とっても可愛い！
The illustration was drawn by Waffle-ko-san. It's so cute!
持ち運びやすいサイズ感なので、ぜひたくさん使ってください！
It's a portable size, so please use it a lot!
2つ目は、こちら。タンブラー！
The second one is this. Tumbler!
イラストは、KEIJOさんに描いていただきました！
The illustration was drawn by KEIJO-san!
今回なんと、コナミさんに特別許諾をいただいて、お品のデザインに寄せさせていただきました！
This time, we actually got special permission from KONAMI to make the design resemble their style!
ムラクモMZDDのオマージュイラストなんですけど
It's an homage illustration of MURAKUMO MZDD.
のんびり寝転ぶフレアの横には、相棒のノア、チョコちゃんとエルフレも一緒の、とっても可愛いイラストとなってます。
Next to Flare lying down relaxedly, her companions Noah, Choco-chan, and Elfriends are there too.
大容量で、1リットルくらい入って、持ち手も付いてて飲みやすいので、ぜひみんなにも使ってほしいです！
It has a large capacity, holds about 1 liter, and has a handle for easy drinking, so I want everyone to use it!
3つ目は、こちら。ぬいぐるみ付きスマホショルダー！
The third one is this. Plushie Smartphone Shoulder Bag!
お出かけ衣装のぬいぐるみが付いた、スマホショルダーです！
It's a smartphone shoulder bag with a plushie in her outing outfit!
ケースではないので、様々な機種のスマホが入るんですけど
It's not a case, so it fits various smartphone models.
全機種対応ではないので、サイズが合わなかった人はスマホ以外の小物を入れてください
It's not compatible with all models, so if the size doesn't fit, please put in other items.
ぜひいろんな場所に連れてってね！
Please take it with you to many places!
4つ目は、こちら。キャップ！
The fourth one is this. Cap!
イラストの私とお揃いのキャップです！
It's a matching cap with the one I'm wearing in the illustration!
今回のコンセプトで、帽子はどうしても外せなかったので
With this concept, a hat was absolutely essential.
前出したものとは、色とデザインを変えてみました
I've changed the color and design from the previous one.
どっかな？可愛いかな？かっこいいかな？
How is it? Is it cute? Is it cool?
シンプルめなデザインなので、季節問わず被れるキャップです。
It's a simple design, so you can wear it regardless of the season.
5つ目は、こちら。シチュエーションボイス！
The fifth one is this. Situation Voice!
フレアと一緒に公園デート！
A park date with Flare!
今回のグッズのイラストに合ったような雰囲気のボイスが付いてます
It includes a situation voice with an atmosphere that matches the illustration.
みんな、よかったら聴いてね！
Everyone, please listen if you like!
最後に、フルセット。数量限定は、直筆メッセージ入りカード！
Lastly, the Full Set. The limited edition includes a card with a handwritten message!
通常版は、箔押し複製メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードが付いてきます！
The regular version comes with an instax-style bromide card with a printed message!
ふぅ、駆け足だったけど、どれも使いやすいと思うので、ぜひ買ってもらえると嬉しいです！
Phew, that was quick, but I think they're all great, so I'd be happy if you bought them!
えー、じゃあ、次の曲に行こうかな？
Well then, shall we move on to the next song?
ゲストはね、ちょっとまだいるので、嬉しい告知とかも残ってる...
There are still some guests, and some happy announcements left...
盛り上がってるかな？
Is everyone getting excited?
みんなまだ帰らないでね。このあとも楽しんでね。
Everyone, don't go home yet. Keep enjoying the rest of the show.
追いかけても　追いかけても
Even if I chase after you, even if I chase after you,
するり指を抜ける　水のような
you slip through my fingers like water.
あなただけに　あなただけに
Only by you, only by you,
見つめられたただ　一つ星の手に
held by the hand of a single star I gazed at.
夢でも　つかまえて
Even if it's a dream, catch me.
朧 / 作詞:Dali. 作曲・編曲:Starving Trancer / Ryu☆
[Title: Oboro / Lyrics: Dali. Comp. & Arr.: Starving Trancer / Ryu☆]
流れる雲に想う
I think of the flowing clouds,
行き先ないこの心
and this heart with nowhere to go.
いつか見た日の明日も
Even the tomorrow of the day I once saw
蒼い通り雨
is a blue passing shower.
色付いた花びら揺らす
Swaying the colored petals,
ぬくもりも激しささえも
even the warmth and the intensity...
せつなさの裏側だけを
only the back side of sadness
残していくくだけの刹那
is left behind in a fleeting moment.
かなうのなら　かなうのなら
If it can come true, if it can come true,
駆け出して行きたい風の中
I want to start running through the wind.
あなただけを　あなただけを
Only you, only you,
見つめたなら羽ばたく蝶のように
if I stare at you, I'll be like a butterfly taking flight.
夢なら　みせないで
If it's a dream, don't show it to me.
星のない夜に密か
Secretly in a starless night,
巡る季節を忘れて
forgetting the passing seasons,
いつか来る日の朝を
the morning of the day that will one day come
隠す涙色
is the color of hidden tears.
絡む指艶めく吐息
Intertwining fingers, glamorous sighs,
昇りつめ落ちゆく心
the heart that rises to the peak and falls.
ひと時のぬくもりさえも
Even the warmth of a moment...
忘れられずにまたひとり孤独
Unable to forget, I'm alone in solitude again.
追いかけたら　追いかけたら
If I chase after you, if I chase after you,
煙り消えてしまう月の影
you're like the moon's shadow vanishing into smoke.
わたしだけに　わたしだけに
Only for me, only for me,
触れられたら煌めく星のように
if I'm touched by you, I'll be like a sparkling star.
嘘なら　抱きしめて
If it's a lie, hold me close.
届くのなら　届くのなら
If it reaches, if it reaches,
明日さえいらない戻らない
I don't even need tomorrow, I'm not going back.
離れてても　離れてても
Even if we're apart, even if we're apart,
心焦がす炎はあなただけ
the flame that burns my heart is for you alone.
追いかけても　追いかけても
Even if I chase after you, even if I chase after you,
するり指を抜ける水のような
you slip through my fingers like water.
わたしだけが　わたしだけが
Only I, only I,
時を止めたようにただ手を伸ばす
just reach out as if time has stopped.
かなうのなら　かなうのなら
If it can come true, if it can come true,
駆け出して行きたい風の中
I want to start running through the wind.
あなただけに　あなただけに
Only for you, only for you,
こころ巡らすはるか朧月
my heart wanders under the distant hazy moon.
嘘でも　抱きしめて
Even if it's a lie, hold me close.
夢なら　醒めないで
If it's a dream, don't wake me up.
世界が輝くその瞬間
The moment the world shines,
ちょっとでも触れたくって
I want to touch it, even a little.
ごらんよ幻をのぞいて
Look, peek into the illusion.
空間が重なって溶けあう
The space overlaps and melts together.
Harmonia / 作詞・作曲・編曲:Konami Arcade Games (PON)
[Title: Harmonia / Lyrics, Comp. & Arr.: Konami Arcade Games (PON)]
太陽と月のように
Like the sun and the moon,
繰り返す空の残像
the repeating afterimage of the sky
時間を超えてはつながる
is connected across time.
響きあうのさ
We resonate.
大胆不敵な空想の輪郭を追いかけて
Chasing the contours of a fearless fantasy,
広がっては飲み込んでいく
spreading and swallowing everything.
世界が輝くその瞬間
The moment the world shines,
ちょっとでも触れたくって
I want to touch it, even a little.
ごらんよ幻をのぞいて
Look, peek into the illusion.
空間を飛び越した
I jumped across space.
未来を追い越すその瞬間
The moment I overtake the future,
いつでもこんなものなのさ
it's always like this.
幻をのぞいた僕らの
Our worlds, which peeked into the illusion,
世界が溶けあう
melt together.
始まりと終わりのように
Just like the beginning and the end,
君に会いに行くよ この感情
I'm coming to see you, with this feeling.
記憶を辿れば つながる
If I trace my memories, we'll connect.
重なり合うよ
We'll overlap.
変幻自在に 組まれた想像の パズルは
The puzzle of imagination, built so ever-changing,
狂おしいほど 美しいのだろう
must be so beautiful it's maddening.
世界を飛び立つ その瞬間 どうしても 見せたくて ごらんよ
The moment I take flight into the world...
I badly want to show you, so look.
見慣れない風景に そうさ今 駆け出した 未来が
Into an unfamiliar landscape...
yes, right now, the future I ran toward...
不安だった 昨日はちっぽけな 何気ない 今日なのさ
the anxious yesterday is now just a tiny, ordinary today.
幻が歪んだ ボクらの 世界が重なる
The distorted illusion—our worlds overlap.
本当はずっと 世界はボクを待ってた
Actually, all along, the world was waiting for me.
本当はずっと ボクもキミを待ってたんだ
Actually, all along, I was waiting for you too.
重なり合った 声が遠く 響いて届く
Our overlapping voices resonate far away and reach out.
聞こえるでしょう 目を開けて
You can hear it, right? Open your eyes.
物語が始まる時さ
It's when the story begins.
世界が輝く その瞬間 ちょっとでも 触れたくて ごらんよ
The moment the world shines...
I want to touch it even a little, so look.
幻をのぞいて 空間を飛び越した 未来を
Looking through the illusion,
at a future that jumped through space...
追い越すその瞬間 いつでも こんなものなのさ
the moment we overtake it, it's always like this.
幻をのぞいた ボクらの 世界が溶け合う
Looking through the illusion, our worlds melt together.
はい！ということで聴いていただきました、
Alright! And that was...
「朧」と「Harmonia」2曲！どうでしたかー？
the two songs, "Oboro" and "Harmonia"! How was it?
「朧」は俺の親友、アイリスと2人で、
For "Oboro," my best friend IRyS and I...
なんとダンス部のダンスを躍らせていただきました！
actually performed the Dance Evolution routine!
めっちゃ難しかったーｗ
It was so hard! lol
どちらもね、大好きな曲なので、今回歌えてすごく嬉しかったです！
They're both songs I love, so I was really happy to sing them today!
はい、ここまでもですね、盛りだくさんだったんですけど、
Yes, it's been packed so far, but...
ちょっとまだですね、嬉しいことがありまして！
there's actually one more thing I'm excited about!
なんとですね、今回ちょっとビッグな方をですね、お呼びさせていただきまして、
In fact, we've invited a very special guest today.
BEMANIシリーズで作曲をしてくださっている方をね、お呼びしたんですけど…
I've called someone who composes for the BEMANI series...
誰かな？誰かな？ちょっと待ってくださいね。誰かな？誰が…
Who could it be? Who could it be? Just a moment. Who is it? Who...
おっ！？
Oh!?
え、だ…いいんですかね？これ。いいですか？
Uh, is... is this okay? This? Is it?
えー、あの、私が一番好きな曲と言っていました、音を作っております、
Well, he created the sounds for the songs I called my favorites...
wacさんです！
It's wac-san!
どうも、よろしくお願いします！
Hello, nice to meet you!
あー！よろしくお願いします！今日はありがとうございます！
Ah! Nice to meet you! Thank you for being here today!
いえいえ、ありがとうございます。
No, no, thank you.
2Dだったんですね、ちょっとｗ
You're in 2D, I see. lol
あります。
I am.
なんか舌も伸びませんでした？
Didn't your tongue just stretch out?
舌はね、伸びるんですよ。ニョーっと。
The tongue, you see, it stretches. Like "nyooo".
あ、結構長い！
Oh, it's quite long!
ま、今日はね、これが精一杯なんですよ。
Well, today, this is my limit.
今日はこれで許して欲しいとのことなんですけど、
He says he wants us to forgive him with just this for today...
あの、ちょっとじゃあ自己紹介をしていただいてもよろしいでしょうか？
but, well, could you please introduce yourself?
あ、おそれいります。
Ah, certainly.
東京都江東区…あ、すごい…言っちゃっていいんですか？
Koto Ward, Tokyo... Oh, wow... are you allowed to say that?
コナミアミューズメントよりやってまいりました、新人VTuberのwacです。よろしくお願いします！
From Konami Amusement, I'm the rookie VTuber, wac. Nice to meet you!
コンワク〜！
Kon-wac!
「誰？」って感じなんですかね？いや、たぶん「何？」って感じなんですかね？
I wonder if people are like "Who?" Or maybe "What?"
最近あの、よくね、LIVELYとかでもやらせていただいているので、
Lately, I've been doing things on LIVELY and such,
結構うちのリスナーとかも知ってるとか、もともと音ゲーマーさんとかも結構知ってくださって見てると思うんで、
so quite a few of my listeners might know him. And I think original rhythm gamers know him and are watching,
あの、wacさんのことは多分知ってると思います。「あれ？これもwacさんなんだ！」みたいなの結構あったりとか。
so I'm sure they know wac-san. Like, "Wait, this was wac-san too!" happens a lot.
そうですね、多ければ多いほど良いものですから、wacは。
Yes, the more wacs there are, the better. wac is a good thing.
いったんちょっとあの、遊ばせていただいた、新筐体の話とか。
Anyway, let's talk about the new cabinet we were playing with earlier.
あ、ぜひ。
Oh, please.
あの、12月18日とかでしたっけ？稼働日は。
Um, was it December 18th? The launch date.
12月18日より順次稼働させていただいております、はい。
We've been rolling them out sequentially since December 18th, yes.
ぴかぴかポップンモデル、さきほど遊ばせていただいたんですけど、
The Pikari-Pikari Pop'n model that I just played with...
いやー可愛いですね、見た目すごい！
man, it looks so cute, the appearance is amazing!
ですよね！
It is, isn't it!
めっちゃ可愛いいっすよね！
It's super cute, right!
個人的に、液晶がめちゃめちゃ明るくて、すごい見やすいです！
Personally, the screen is incredibly bright and very easy to see!
でっかいっすもんね。
It's huge, after all.
そうなんですよ。大きければ大きいほど良いですからね。
Exactly. The bigger, the better.
大きければ大きいほどいいです、はい。何事も。
The bigger, the better, yes. For everything.
あとあの、キャラクターがね、昔のキャラクターとかもすごい綺麗に映ったりするの…
And the characters, even the old ones, are displayed so beautifully...
はい。
Yes.
そうですね。今皆さんも本当ね、今回ピカピカポップ君モデルが完成するまでには、もうポップンスタッフのみんなもそうですけども、
That's right. Everyone, really, until this Pika Pika Pop-kun model was completed, not only the pop'n staff...
デスロウ先生や、DJ良孝さんや、PONさんや、猫又マスターさんや、Takaさんや、あさきさんや、
but also Des-ROW-sensei, DJ Yoshitaka-san, PON-san, Nekomata Master-san, Taka-san, Asaki-san...
劇団レコードさん、K-Zくん、Tatshくん、もういっぱいです。
Gekidan Record-san, K-Z-kun, Tatsh-kun... there are so many of them.
土台作っていただいた方々もいらっしゃいますし、土台運んでくださった方々もいらっしゃいますし。
There are people who built the foundation, and people who carried it here.
はい。
Yes.
感謝の気持ちで、わたくし生きております。
I live my life filled with gratitude.
はい。
Yes.
はい。この場に立てたのも、皆さんのおかげでございます。
Yes. It's thanks to everyone that I can stand here.
はい。ありがとうございます。いや、それは本当にこちらこそありがとうございますなんですけれども。
Yes, thank you. No, really, I'm the one who should be saying thank you.
いえいえ。
Not at all.
この辿り着けたのも、はい、いろんな方々のご尽力あってのことでございますので。
Getting this far was only possible due to the efforts of many people.
はい。ということなんですけれども、ポップンミュージックの何か初出し情報とかあります？
Right. So, do you have any exclusive info on pop'n music?
それはちょっと。
That's a bit...
あ、言えない？
Oh, you can't say?
いや、言います。
No, I will.
どっちだ。
Which is it?
初出し情報って何がいいですか？
What kind of exclusive info would you like?
私一個人としてはやっぱりMZDの話とか聞きたいんですけど。
Personally, I'd love to hear something about MZD.
MZD。
MZD...
神ですね。
He's a god.
神だから神、お神の神ですね。
He's a god, so he's the god of gods.
はい。一番好きですし、あの、結構やっぱwacさんって、あの、MZDのなんか半分くらいだと思ってて。
Yes. He's my favorite. And I feel like wac-san is about half of MZD.
半分。
Half?
あのやっぱ半分はPONさんなんですよ。
And the other half is PON-san.
えっとね、厳密に言うとMぐらいですね。
Well, strictly speaking, he's about the "M".
ZがPONさんで、Dがその他みんなみたいな。くらいの配分ですね。
"Z" is PON-san, and "D" is everyone else. That's about the ratio.
あー、なるほどなるほど。確かにな。なので、ちょっとMZDの話、ちょっともし話せる範囲で聞けたら嬉しいなー、なんて。
Ah, I see, I see. True. So, if you could tell me anything about MZD...
なるほど。MZDの何を知りたいんだい？
I see. What do you want to know about MZD?
あ、キャラ設定とか。
Like his character settings and such.
あー、なんかアマゾン川流域、青木町ですね。何でか知らんですが。
Ah, the Amazon River basin, Aoki-cho. No idea why, though.
何知らんのかい。
You don't know why?!
でもなんか昔なんかアマゾンみたいな槍持ってましたよね。
But long ago, he used to carry a spear like an Amazonian, right?
影がですね。
His shadow did.
影がですね。あれがアマゾンなのかもしれない。違うのかもしれない。
His shadow, yeah. That might be the Amazon element. Or maybe not.
アマゾン要素そこなんですね。
So that's the Amazon connection?
うん、多分。
Yeah, probably.
今も青木町に住んでるんですかね。
Is he still living in Aoki-cho?
多分住んでる。
Probably.
これなんか、あれですね、公式さんと話す話か。
This feels like a conversation one should have with the official staff...
あの、ポップはね、本当に公式が知らないこといっぱいあるんですよ。
Well, in pop'n, there's a lot the "official" side doesn't know.
あ、そうなんですね。
Oh, is that so?
はい。皆さんの、あの、いろんな思いで出来てるので。生半可公式こそ知らないこともいっぱいあるんで。
Yes. It's built on everyone's various feelings. So there's plenty the official side isn't aware of.
ああ。後からついたりとかすることもあるんですか。
I see. Do settings get added later on?
なんか曲とかって、あの、曲作ってからキャラクターとか決まるんですか？それともキャラクターに当てて曲作ったりするんですか？
Regarding songs, is the character decided after the song is made? Or is the song made for a specific character?
おお、なるほど。結構ケースバイケースっていうか、特にMZDとかは本当に、でもMZDって決まってること多いっすね。やっぱり。
Oh, I see. It's mostly case-by-case... but for MZD, things are usually decided beforehand.
ああ、そうですよね。
Ah, I thought so.
わりとバージョンの最後に入ってきたりすることが多いんで、MZDありきで曲作んなきゃいけないことは多いです。
He often appears at the end of a version, so songs are often made specifically for him.
はい。特にこのキャラ好きな人がこのキャラに曲書きたいって場合もあります。
Yes. Sometimes someone who loves the character wants to write a song for them.
ああー、なるほどー。え、新しいハイチェアーズにもMZDが出てくると、フレアは期待しているんですけど。
Ah, I see. Flare is hoping MZD will appear in the new High-Cheers too.
出るのかな？
I wonder if he will?
出るのかな？あのうさねこの時みたいにストーリー結構しっかり見たいのって、今後もあったりとかするんですか。
I wonder? Will there be more deep stories like in Usaneko in the future?
はい、なんかストーリー、どうなんですかね、あのポップンお好きな方って、そういうストーリー的な、このキャラこんなんだったんだー、みたいなのがわかるのが嬉しいのか。
Well, for the story... I wonder if pop'n fans enjoy learning about the characters' backgrounds like that.
めっちゃ嬉しいですよ、もう本で出してほしいまである。はい。なんか推しの情報を常に募集しているので。お願いします。
It's incredibly exciting! I even want a book about it. I'm always looking for info on my favorites. Please!
マジですか？頼まれちゃいました。いや、大先輩のお願いとあってはね。いいですね。欲張りな人大好きですよ、はい。
Really? You've asked for it. Well, since it's a request from a senior... I like greedy people.
あの、私、実は今日誕生日なんですけど。
Um, actually, today is my birthday.
え、マジすか。
Oh, really?
そうなんです。
Yes.
おめでト、誕生日歌いましょうか。
Congrats! Shall we sing "Happy Birthday"?
あ、歌ってくれるんですか。
Oh, you'll sing for me?
おめでト、おたんじょーびー
Happy birthday to you~
レアですよ。これ今日実装されます？
That's so rare! Will this be implemented today?
ありますか。
Think so?
あの、誕生日なんで、もしよろしければ、サインとかいただけたら嬉しいなーと。
Since it's my birthday, I'd be happy if I could get an autograph.
サイン！そんなん、なんぼでもしますよ。借用書とかじゃなければ、全然全然書きます書きます。
An autograph! I'll do as many as you want. As long as it's not an IOU, I'll definitely sign.
あの、今日、2枚ちょっとサインカード用意したんで。好きな方、やっぱり音ゲーマーといえばカードなんで。
I've prepared two cards for you to sign. After all, rhythm gamers are all about the cards.
e-amusement passをちょっと2枚用意しました。普通のオーソドックスなやつと、仕事猫のカードちょっと用意したんで、猫なだけに。
I have two e-amusement passes. One standard and one with Shigo-Neko... because you're a cat.
なるほど。猫だけに。
I see. Because I'm a cat.
はい。どちらでも、どちらにもサインしてもらえたら嬉しい。ここら辺にきっと後で出していただくかなーと思うので。
Yes. I'd be happy if you could sign both. I'm sure they'll appear around here later.
大丈夫です。書きます書きます。任せてください。描き尽くします。埋め尽くします。
No problem. I'll sign them. Leave it to me. I'll fill them with my writing.
描き尽くす。ありがとうございます。
Fill them? Thank you.
すべてを消し去る勢いで描き尽くします。
I'll write so much it'll cover everything else!
あわよくば、私BEMANIの楽曲が大好きなので、いつかカバーとか入ったら嬉しいなー、とかってちょっと、思って。
Also, if possible... I love BEMANI songs, so I was thinking it'd be nice to do a cover someday.
おや。おやおや。
Oh? Oh ho?
あ、ちょっと欲張りすぎました。ごめんなさい。いや、フレアさん、お待たせしました。
Ah, maybe I'm being too greedy. Sorry... (Cat) No, Flare-san, thanks for waiting.
案件です。
This is a sponsored project.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ここまで溜めて、溜めに溜めて案件ございます。
We've been saving this announcement... it's a project!
...ありませんでした。
...didn't happen.
なんですが、今回なんと今わっくんさんが言ってくださった通り、
However, this time, as Wakku-san just said,
ちょっと不知火フレア、BEMANIコラボ決定しました！ありがとうございます！
Shiranui Flare's BEMANI collaboration has been confirmed! Thank you!
やったー！やりましたね！
We did it! You did it!
おめでとうございます。ありがとうございます。めちゃめちゃ嬉しいです。
Congratulations. Thank you so much. I'm so happy.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
なんか、えっと、どこを触れていいのかなと...
I wonder which part I should touch upon...
どのゲームとしましょうかっていう話ですね。
You mean which game we should talk about.
ポップン、ポップン、ポップン...
Pop'n, Pop'n, Pop'n...
まあそうですね、ポップンさすがにここでしなかったらわけがわからないんですけども、ここまでして。
Well, yes. It'd be confusing if we didn't do Pop'n after all this.
そうですよね。
Right?
もちろんポップンもですけど、さらに今回、
Of course Pop'n, but also this time,
サウンドボルテックスと、ダンスダンスレボリューションと、3機種でのコラボをさせていただきたいと思っております！
Sound Voltex and DDR. We're collaborating with three titles!
すごーい！
Amazing!
これはあの、私の曲が収録される...
Does this mean my songs will be...
それはもちろん、もちろん曲ですよ。新曲行きましょうよ。
Of course! It's about the songs. Let's go with a new song.
新曲！？
A new song!?
実はね、ちょっとね、この人がいいんじゃないかなと思ってるんですよね、曲作ってもらうなら。
Actually, I have someone in mind to compose it.
誰なんだろう？
I wonder who it is?
先ほどMとかZとかDとか言ってたんで。
Since we were talking about M, Z, and D earlier...
今回はそのZにお願いしようかなと思ってます。
I think I'll ask "Z" this time.
Zって誰だっけ？えっとZ...Z誰だっけ...？
Who was "Z" again? Um, "Z"... who was it?
「ぽ」です。「ぽ」。「ぽ」です。
It's "Po". "Po". It's "Po".
「ぽ」「ぽ」「ぽ」...「ポン」です。
Po-Po-Po... it's "PON".
P・O・N、PONというね、なかなかいい曲を書く子がいるんですよ。
P-O-N, PON. There's a guy who writes some really good songs.
ポップンミュージック、先ほど、そうですね、フレアさんのM2Uさんの曲がお好きって言ってましたけど、
Earlier you mentioned you liked M2U's songs, Flare-san.
まあ1/3くらい作って、最近結構M2Uの曲いっぱいまた作ってますし、
He's composed about a third of them, and lately he's making more.
まあ本人も歌うし、女性ボーカリストの曲もいっぱい書いてるような。
He sings himself, and writes many songs for female vocalists.
私、わっくんさんとPONさんが一番好きなんですよね。
I actually like Wakku-san and PON-san the best.
マジすか、ありがとうございます。恐縮です。恥ずかしくて隠れちゃいます。
Really? Thank you. I'm honored. I'm so embarrassed I'll hide.
あ、隠れちゃった。出てきてください。
Oh, he hid! Please come back out.
ありがとうございます。楽しみ待ってます。
Thank you. I'll be looking forward to it.
せっかくなんですけど、わっくんさん来ていただいたから、
Since you're here, Wakku-san...
なんかよかったら実機に収録される楽曲をわっくんさんと一緒にやりたいなと思うんですけど。
I'd love to perform the song going into the game with you.
歌います？
Would you sing?
いいでしょう。せっかくなんで、2人だけでやりましょう。
Sure. Since we're at it, let's do it with just the two of us.
あの、ピアノと歌だけで。
Just piano and vocals.
え！？いいんですか！？めちゃめちゃ嬉しい、緊張します。
What!? Is that okay!? I'm so happy, but I'm nervous.
めちゃくちゃ緊張してますけど、自分も。
I'm incredibly nervous too.
頑張ります！頑張ります！
I'll do my best!
頑張ります。実はね、練習してます、自分。このために。
I'll do my best. Actually, I've been practicing for this.
マジですか。楽しみ。
Seriously? I can't wait.
ぜひ聞いていただきたい。
I'd love for you to hear it.
では、フレア、わっくんさんによる、聞いてください。「僕の飛行機」。
Now then, by Flare and Wakku-san, please listen to: "My Paper Plane".
どこまで飛べるかを
Where can we fly to?
確かめに僕ら旅に出る
We're setting off on a trip to find out
夢は尽きることを忘れて
Forgetting the dreams that run out
草原を駆け抜けて行ったけど
We ran through the meadows
幼い憧れと
With childish longing and
ほどけた指切り 絆にする
With unraveled pinky promises we make bonds
逃げ出せないから ただ空を見てた
Because we can't escape, we just looked at the sky
かっこ悪いから 嘘をついた
Because it's uncool, I told a lie
白いノート1枚破って
I tore up one sheet of white notebook paper
今日の日付とさよなら
Today's date and goodbye
託した紙飛行機
Entrusted paper plane
風に乗って舞い上がって
Ride the wind and soar
蒼く溶けた
Melting into the blue
旅立ちの歌を背に 白い軌道追いかけて
With the song of departure on our backs, chasing the white trail
ここで見てた淡い夢も 翼にして
The faint dream we watched here too, make it into wings
いつか誰かに届いてくれる?
And someday, will it reach someone?
僕の飛行機
My paper plane
乗り込んだ汽車が
The train I boarded
見上げてた空へ
Towards the sky I was looking up at
続くなら
If it continues
夢をみてた 遠い日々に
In the distant days when I was dreaming
取り残されてる記憶は
The memories left behind
まだあの空を覚えてるから
Still remember that sky
絡み合って もつれ合って やがて独り
Intertwined, tangled, and eventually alone
さよならの歌 胸に約束を数えてるけど
Counting the promises in my heart, a song of goodbye
ここで見てた 淡い夢も 翼にして
Making the faint dreams I saw here into wings
きっとどこまでも 追いつけると 信じてる
I believe I can catch up to it surely anywhere
風に乗って 舞い上がって 蒼く溶けた
Riding the wind, soaring high, it melted into blue
あの紙飛行機は 誰の手に届いたろうか
I wonder whose hand that paper airplane reached
夢が覚めて 僕が空に還る時も
When the dream wakes and I return to the sky
ずっと変わらずに 僕は君の中に生きている
I'll keep living inside you, unchanging
うわあ！アレンジすごい！
Wow! The arrangement is amazing!
え、ありがとうございます。
Um, thank you very much.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
めちゃめちゃ貴重な体験をさせていただきまして。
I was allowed to have a very precious experience.
こちらこそ、はい。ありがとうございました。
Likewise. Yes, thank you very much.
はい、ありがとうございました！ワックさんでした！
Yes, thank you very much! That was WAX-san!
はい、wacこと脇田潤です。
Yes, I'm Jun Wakita, also known as wac.
一言、最後にあります？
Do you have a final word?
いえ、もう本当、この度は素晴らしい機会をいただきまして、こちらこそありがとうございます。
No, really, thank you very much for giving me this wonderful opportunity.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
今後とも是非ポップンミュージック、BEMANIシリーズをよろしくお願いいたします。
Please continue to support Pop'n Music and the BEMANI series.
よろしくお願いします！
Please do!
はあ〜、いや〜、本当に嬉しいですね。
Haa~, wow~, I'm really happy.
大好きな「紙飛行機」をワックさんと一緒にお届けしました。
I performed my favorite 'Kami Hikouki' with WAX-san.
アレンジバージョンどうでしたか？めっちゃすごかったですよね！
How was the arranged version? It was so amazing, right!
ワックさんからご提案いただきまして、今回アレンジバージョンで歌わせていただきました。めちゃめちゃ嬉しい。
WAX-san suggested it, so I sang the arranged version this time. I'm so happy.
もうなんか思い残すことがない…あ、まだ思い残すことはたくさんある。
I feel like I have nothing left to regret... Oh, wait, I still have plenty left.
ね、まだコラボとかもありますからね。
Right, we still have collaborations and stuff.
あ、でですね、あの、ここで新曲が出ます！
Ah, and also, um, a new song is coming out here!
なんかヌルッと出てきたんですけど、これさっき言ってたワックさんが言ってたPONさんのとかじゃなくて、私個人の新曲が出ます。
It just sort of slipped out, but this isn't the one by PON-san WAX-san mentioned, it's my own personal new song.
「Silent Flame, Never Fade」という曲になります。
The song is called 'Silent Flame, Never Fade'.
作詞作曲がですね、fripSideの八木沼悟志さんに作っていただきました。
The lyrics and composition were done by Satoshi Yaginuma of fripSide.
配信の後、MVも出ますのでお楽しみに、ということなんですが。
The MV will also be released after the stream, so please look forward to it.
こちらデジタルリリースはこの後0時からとなっております。
The digital release will be at midnight after this.
そしてですね、なんと。
And then, what's more...
この新曲「Silent Flame, Never Fade」が、ポップンミュージック、ダンスダンスレボリューション、サウンドボルテックスの3機種になんと収録されます！すげー！
This new song 'Silent Flame, Never Fade' will be included in Pop'n Music, DDR, and Sound Voltex! Amazing!
マジか！なんか感想って言ってたけど「マジか」しかちょっと出てこないんですけど。
Really?! They asked for my thoughts, but all I can say is 'Are you serious?!'
はい、ありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you very much.
この他の詳細もですね、生誕グッズも含めて、ちょっと最後に改めてお知らせしますので、お待ちください。
I'll announce other details, including birthday goods, again at the end, so please wait.
ではですね、早速今お知らせしました新曲を聴きたいとおもいますので、お披露目しようかなと思います。
Well then, I'd like to listen to the new song I just announced, so I'm going to debut it.
それでは聴いてください。「Silent Flame, Never Fade」。
Please listen to it. 'Silent Flame, Never Fade'.
静かに揺れ続ける焔
The flame that continues to sway quietly
名もなき道照らし出す
Illuminating the nameless road
失くしていた未来さえ
Even the future that was lost
いまあなたと 新たな明日を刻んだ
I've carved a new tomorrow with you now
いくつもの夜を超えて
Crossing over many nights,
紡いできた 自分らしさ
I have spun my own way of being.
選択したその全てが
Everything I have chosen...
私をまた突き動かす
...moves me forward once again.
強がってた訳じゃなくて
It's not that I was acting tough,
止まることが怖かったよ
I was just afraid to stop.
迷っていたあの日もきっと
Even those days I was lost,
今のチカラになってるよ
I'm sure have become the strength I have now.
一人きりだと思っても
Even when I think I am all alone,
気づけばそこにある笑顔が
if I notice, the smiles are there.
私といつも一緒に歩いてくれてた
You have always walked together with me.
その意味 そのチカラ 絶対に離さない！
I will never let go of that meaning, that strength!
加速していくこの想いは
This desire that is accelerating...
いま翼を纏い出す
...is now starting to wear wings.
私が私でいれる
Just being able to be myself...
それだけで十分だから
...is enough.
逃げないって決めたのは
The reason I decided not to run away...
強くなったからじゃない
...is not because I became strong.
私を呼ぶその声と
With that voice that calls me,
重ね合った 信じる世界の明日を
we overlap the tomorrow of the world we believe in.
傷つくこと 躊躇ってた
I was hesitant to get hurt,
立ち止まったこともあった
there were times I stood still.
そんな時に この背中を
At such times, you pushed my back,
押してくれたその眼差し
that look in your eyes.
迷いながら選んだ道
The path I chose while lost,
間違いさえ真実だと
even the mistakes are the truth.
その焔は闇を照らして
That flame lights up the darkness,
私に正しさをくれた
and gave me righteousness.
張り裂けそうに痛んでも
Even if it hurts until it tears apart,
この胸に刻んだ勇気が
this courage carved in my chest...
私をいつも支えてくれていたから
...has always supported me.
今ここに感じ合う
Now we feel it here together,
あなたと私の夢
your and my dream.
燃え尽きることの無い夢は
The dream that never burns out...
この大空に羽ばたいて
...flaps its wings in this great sky.
涙さえも輝かせ
Making even tears shine,
誰かの夜を照らしたい
I want to light up someone's night.
逃げないって決めたのは
The reason I decided not to run away...
強くなったからじゃない
...is not because I became strong.
静かな焔(ほのお)を抱いて
Embracing the quiet flame,
何度だって立ち上がれること知ったから
I learned that I can get back up no matter how many times.
たとえ世界が色を失くし
Even if the world loses its color,
光が遠ざかっても
and the light moves far away...
この名に刻む焔(ほむら)は
...the flame carved into this name...
あなたと私を繋いで
...will connect you and me.
逃げないって決めたのは
The reason I decided not to run away...
強くなったからじゃない
...is not because I became strong.
私を呼ぶその声と
With that voice that calls me,
重ね合った 信じる世界の明日を
we overlap the tomorrow of the world we believe in.
この後詳細お知らせ！ まだ帰らないでね！
[Screen Text: Details announced later! Don't leave yet!]
不知火フレア2026 BEMANI楽曲3Dライブ 見てくれて本当にありがとうございました
Shiranui Flare 2026 BEMANI Song 3D Live. Thank you so much for watching!
今回のこのコラボは 本当に生誕ライブを企画する際に最初から決まっていたものではなく
This collaboration wasn't actually something decided from the beginning when planning the birthday live.
みんなが声を上げて盛り上げてくれたから 叶った案件なので
It's a project that came true because everyone spoke up and cheered for it.
改めて皆さんに お礼を言わせてください 本当にありがとうございました
So let me say thank you to everyone once again. Thank you very much!
よし！ 気になる不知火フレアBEMANIコラボ
Alright! The much-anticipated Shiranui Flare BEMANI collaboration...
コラボの詳しい...
The details of the collaboration...
ではないよ！内容、発表していくよ！
That's not all! I'm going to announce the details!
改めて、今回コラボするゲームは...
Once again, the games we're collaborating with are...
pop'n music、DanceDanceRevolution、
SOUND VOLTEXの3機種です！
pop'n music, DanceDanceRevolution,
and SOUND VOLTEX—these three games!
この3機種に、先ほど披露した
「Silent Flame, Never Fade」が収録されます！
My original song "Silent Flame, Never Fade,"
which I just performed, will be included in them!
ご覧の日時からプレイすることができますので、
お楽しみに！
You can play it starting from the date shown,
so look forward to it!
さらにさらに、不知火フレアが歌う
BEMANIシリーズのカバー楽曲の収録も決定しました！
And that's not all! We've also decided to include
BEMANI series covers sung by Shiranui Flare!
収録楽曲、収録機種、収録日時については、
ご覧の通りです。
The included songs, games, and dates
are as shown here.
そして、まだまだ終わりません！
And it's not over yet!
BEMANIアーティストとの
コラボ新曲の制作が決定しました！
Production of a new collaboration song
with a BEMANI artist has been decided!
続報は、pop'n music公式Xで発信予定ですので、
ぜひチェックしてみてください。
Further news will be posted on the official
pop'n music X account, so be sure to check it out.
さあ、ここからは各機種ごとの
コラボ内容をまとめてご紹介していきます。
Now, I'll introduce the collaboration details
for each game.
pop'n musicでは、なんと不知火フレアが
ポップンキャラとして登場しちゃいます！
In pop'n music, Shiranui Flare will
actually appear as a pop'n character!
さらに、ゲームをもっと楽しくプレイできる、
コラボカスタマイズアイテムも登場します。
Additionally, collaboration customization items
will be available to make the game even more fun.
詳細は追って公式Xにて発表する予定なので、
お見逃しなく！
Details will be announced later on
the official X account, so don't miss it!
DanceDanceRevolutionでは、プレミアムカスタマイザー
としてコラボアイテムが登場予定です。
In DanceDanceRevolution, collaboration items will
appear as Premium Customizers.
SOUND VOLTEXでは、NEMESYSクルーに、
不知火フレアも新加入します！
In SOUND VOLTEX, Shiranui Flare will
join the NEMESYS Crew!
さらに、カスタマイズアイテムとして登場予定です。
Also, she'll appear as a customization item.
こちらも詳細は追って公式Xにて発表していくので、
忘れずにチェックしてね！
Details for this will also be announced on the official
X account, so don't forget to check it!
ということで、今回はフレアがずっと愛してやまない
BEMANIシリーズのオリジナルソング縛りのライブがしたいというね...
So, this live was born from my desire to do a show
exclusively featuring songs from the BEMANI series...
あの、完全にフレアのやりたい放題ライブの
企画だったわけなんですが...
...which I've loved forever. It was completely
a "do whatever I want" live project...
そこからこんなにたくさんゲームに実装されてしまうなんて、
今だにちょっと現実味がありませんが...
...but I still can't believe so many things are
actually being implemented into the games...
長らく愛しているBEMANIユーザー様も、末永く今後とも
BEMANIシリーズのことをよろしくお願いします。
To the long-time BEMANI users, I hope you'll
continue to support the series for a long time to come.
あ、不知火フレアも良ければよろしくお願いします。
And, if you'd like, please support Shiranui Flare as well.
ということで、音ゲーマー特有の誰視点ですが...
既に遊んでいるエルフレはもちろん...
So, from the perspective of a rhythm gamer...
to the Elfriends who already play, and of course...
まだ始めてないエルフレも、これを機に
遊んでもらえたら嬉しいです。
...to those who haven't started yet, I'd be happy
if you'd take this opportunity to give it a try.
そして新曲もね、このあとMVが公開されるのと、
0時にはリリースもされるので、たくさん聴いて、見てね。
And for the new song, the MV will be out soon, and it
releases at midnight, so please listen and watch it a lot.
あと、グッズ。今回ですね、少し早めにお知らせさせて
いただいたので、さらっと振り返るね。
Also, the merchandise. Since I announced it
a bit early this time, let's do a quick review.
タオル、タンブラー、スマホショルダー、
キャップ、ボイス、フルセット。
Towel, tumbler, smartphone shoulder bag,
cap, voice, and the full set.
どれも可愛いので、お仕事やお出かけ、
ゲームセンターとか行ったり、何でも使ってみてください。
They're all cute, so please use them for work,
going out, or even when you go to the arcade!
グッズの販売はこのあと21時半からなので、
数量限定もたくさん用意しているから、焦らずにね。
Sales start at 21:30. We have plenty of
limited-edition items, so no need to rush.
裏話なんかは、また改めてお話しさせてください。
I'll share some behind-the-scenes stories another time.
今回は思いもよらないことが本当にたくさん起きて、
皆様に感謝の気持ちでいっぱいです。
So many unexpected things happened this time,
and I'm full of gratitude for everyone.
本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you so very much.
さ、明日はゲームセンターに行っちゃう？
ねえ、一緒に行こう。
So, are you going to the arcade tomorrow?
Hey, let's go together.